<topic>
	<head>
		<title>Clone Results</title>
		<keywords>
			<f1keyword term="CloneDetective.UI.CloneResults" />
		</keywords>
		<links>
			<link href="CloneExplorer.html">Clone Explorer</link>
			<link href="CloneIntersections.html">Clone Intersections</link>
		</links>
	</head>
	<body>
		<summary>
			<p>
				The Clone Results tool window provides you with a list of clone
				class search results.
			</p>
			<p>
				To access Clone Results, select <b>Clone Results</b> on the
				<b>View</b> - <b>Other Windows</b> menu.
			</p>
		</summary>

		<section title="Representation">
			<p>
				The searches are triggered by some other window, e.g. by using
				<a href="CloneIntersections.html">Clone Intersections</a> or the
				<a href="CodeEditor.html">code editor</a>.
			</p>
			<p>
				Each result is contained in a tab of its own. The header shows the
				ID of searched clone class.
			</p>
			<img src="CloneResults.png" />
			<p>
				In the sample above the clone class <b>227</b> contains clones in three
				files.
			</p>
			<p>
				The bar charts show a graphical representation of the file content and clone distribution.
				The wider the bar, the more source code the file contains. Instead of displaying the content
				in top-down fashion, the bars are displayed left-right. That means that the first line
				is at the left side while the last line is at the right side. Since all clones belong to the
				same clone class all clones are colored in a single color, which is purple.
			</p>
			<p>
				For the sample above this provides you with the following pieces of information:
			</p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					MethodInvocationExpression.cs is the biggest file but it is not much larger than
					FunctionInvocationExpression.cs.
				</li>
				<li>
					AggregateExpression.cs is the smallest file.
				</li>
				<li>
					All occurrences of the clone class 227 are in the upper part of a file.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</section>

		<section title="Navigation">
			<p>
				The Clone Results tool window allows you to easily open the files and navigate to
				the duplicated source code. For this you only have to right click the file. In the
				context menu you see all clones contained in that file. Click the clone you want to open.
			</p>
			<img src="CloneResultsContextMenu.png" />
			<p>
				The file will be opened in the code editor and the cloned source code is selected.
			</p>
			<note>
				Double clicking the file will open it and select the first clone. This is handy for files
				that only contain one clone.
			</note>
		</section>
	</body>
</topic>
