<topic>
	<head>
		<title>Clone Explorer</title>
		<keywords>
			<f1keyword term="CloneDetective.UI.CloneExplorer" />
		</keywords>
		<links>
			<link href="CloneIntersections.html">Clone Intersections</link>
			<link href="CloneResults.html">Clone Results</link>
		</links>
	</head>
	<body>
		<summary>
			<p>
				Clone Explorer provides you with an organized view of your files as well as rolled-up clone
				metrics such as <b>Clone Percentage</b>. A toolbar associated with this window offers commands
				to start and stop Clone Detective as well as importing a Clone Detective result file.
			</p>
			<p>
				To access Clone Explorer, select <b>Clone Explorer</b> on the <b>View</b> - <b>Other Windows</b> menu.
			</p>
		</summary>
		
		<section title="Toolbar Icons">
			<p>
				Clone Explorer has a toolbar that offers several commands:
			</p>
			<img src="CloneExplorerToolbar.png" />
			<table>
				<tr>
					<td>Icon</td>
					<td>Name</td>
					<td>Description</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<img src="Run.png" />
					</td>
					<td>
						Run Clone Detective
					</td>
					<td>
						Starts clone detection.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<img src="Stop.png" />
					</td>
					<td>
						Stop Clone Detective
					</td>
					<td>
						Stops clone detection.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<img src="EditSolutionSettings.png" />
					</td>
					<td>
						Edit Solution Settings
					</td>
					<td>
						Allows customizing <a href="SolutionSettings.html">Solution Settings</a>.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<img src="Import.png" />
					</td>
					<td>
						Import Clone Detective Results
					</td>
					<td>
						Imports a clone detection result file produced by another run, e.g.
						a nightly build.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<img src="Export.png" />
					</td>
					<td>
						Export Clone Detective Results
					</td>
					<td>
						Exports a clone detection result file to an XML file.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<img src="CloseResults.png" />
					</td>
					<td>
						Close Clone Detective Results
					</td>
					<td>
						Unloads current clone detective results. To load the results again, please click "Run Clone Detective".
					</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
		</section>

		<section title="Rollup Metrics">
			<p>
				Clone Explorer offers several different metrics that can be shown for files. They are automatically
				recursively rolled up to their parent directories. The following table lists all metrics:
			</p>
			<table>
				<tr>
					<th>Metric</th>
					<th>Description</th>
					<th>Rollup Action</th>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<b>None</b>
					</td>
					<td>
						This option disables the display of metrics.
					</td>
					<td>
						None
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<b>Number of Clones</b>
					</td>
					<td>
						This metric represents the absolute number of clones found in the given
						file or directory.
					</td>
					<td>
						This metric is rolled up by summing the number of clones.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<b>Number of Clone Classes</b>
					</td>
					<td>
						This metric represents the absolute number of clone classes found in the
						given file or directory.
					</td>
					<td>
						This metric is rolled up by determining the number of elements contained
						in the union of all clone classes.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<b>Number of Cloned Lines</b>
					</td>
					<td>
						This metric represents the absolute number of lines that are contained in
						at least one clone. In other words, the number of lines that are duplicated
						somewhere else.
					</td>
					<td>
						This metric is rolled up by summing the number of cloned lines.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<b>Number of Lines</b>
					</td>
					<td>
						This metric represents the absolute number of lines contained in the given file
						or directory. Also called Lines of Code (LoC).
					</td>
					<td>
						This metric is rolled up by summing the number of lines.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<b>Clone Percentage</b>
					</td>
					<td>
						This metric represents the percentage of code that is duplicated somewhere
						else. It is calcuated by this formula:<br/>
						<c xml:space="preserve">[Number of Cloned Lines] / [Number of Lines]</c>
					</td>
					<td>
						This metric is rolled up by this formula:<br/>
						<c xml:space="preserve">[Rolled-up Number of Cloned Lines] / [Rolled-up Number of Lines]</c>
					</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
			<note>
				<p>
					Files and directories for which no value is displayed have a value of zero.
					This makes reading much easier as it highlights the hot spots and avoids the
					impression that you cannot see the forest for the trees.
				</p>
			</note>
		</section>

		<section title="Statusbar">
			<p>
				Clone Explorer has a statusbar that indicates the execution status of Clone Detective.
			</p>
			<img src="CloneExplorerStatusbar.png" />
			<table>
				<tr>
					<th>Icon</th>
					<th>Name</th>
					<th>Description</th>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<img src="Running.png" />
					</td>
					<td>
						Running
					</td>
					<td>
						Indicates that the clone detection is executing.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<img src="Succeeded.png" />
					</td>
					<td>
						Succeeded
					</td>
					<td>
						Indicates that the clone detection was successful and produced a result.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<img src="Error.png" />
					</td>
					<td>
						Error
					</td>
					<td>
						Indicates that the clone detection could not be performed due to an error.
						Click the link to review the log file.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>
						<img src="Stopped.png" />
					</td>
					<td>
						Stopped
					</td>
					<td>
						Indicates that the clone detection was cancelled by the user.
					</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
		</section>
	</body>
</topic>
