<topic>
	<head>
		<title>Solution Settings</title>
		<keywords>
			<f1keyword term="CloneDetective.UI.SolutionSettings" />
		</keywords>
	</head>
	<body>
		<summary>
			<p>
				Allows customizing solution-specific settings of Clone Detective that affect
				the way the clone detection is performed.
			</p>
			<p>
				To access this dialog box, on the toolbar of <b><a href="CloneExplorer.html">Clone Explorer</a></b>,
				click <b>Edit Solution Settings</b>.
			</p>
		</summary>
		<section title="Settings">
			<p>
				The solution-specific settings are stored in a file that follows the pattern
				<c>&lt;SolutionName&gt;.CloneDetective.user</c>. For example, if your solution
				is named <c>MySolution1.sln</c> the settings are stored in the file
				<c>MySolution.CloneDetective.user</c>.				
			</p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					<b>Use custom clone analysis</b>. Specifies whether you want to use a custom clone analysis
					file. If this check box is not checked Clone Detective uses default settings.
				</li>
				<li>
					<b>Analysis file</b>. In this text box you must specify the fully qualified path of the ConQAT
					analysis file that is used to perform the clone detection.
				</li>
				<li>
					<b>Clone result file</b>. In this text box you must specify the fully qualified path of the
					clone results XML file that will be produced by the ConQAT analysis.
				</li>
				<li>
					<b>ConQAT parameter overrides</b>. This section allows you to override properties defined in
					the ConQAT analysis file with other values. These values are passed to ConQAT using the <c>-p</c>
					command line switch.
				</li>
			</ul>
			<note>
				All settings are only applicable if you enabled custom clone clone analysis settings by
				checking <b>Use custom clone analysis</b>.
			</note>
		</section>
		<section title="Macros">
			<p>
				You can only use fully qualified (i.e. absolute) paths for both the ConQAT analysis file and the
				clone results file. If you want to specify paths that are relative to the solution you must use one
				of the macros listed in the table below.
			</p>
			<note>
				Please note that the macros are also available in the property overrides section.
			</note>
			<table>
				<tr>
					<th>Macro</th>
					<th>Example</th>
					<th>Description</th>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>$(InstallDir)</td>
					<td>C:\Program Files (x86)\Clone Detective\</td>
					<td>
						Contains the installation directory of Clone Detection (including the trailing backslash).
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>$(ConQATDir)</td>
					<td>C:\Program Files (x86)\Clone Detective\ConQAT\</td>
					<td>
						Contains the ConQAT directory (including the trailing backslash).
						<note>
							The value is determined by the path to the ConQAT batch file, i.e. depending
							on what you configured in <a href="GobalSettings.html">Global Settings</a> for <b>ConQAT file name</b>.
						</note>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>$(DevEnvDir)</td>
					<td>C:\Program Files (x86)\Microsoft Visual Studio 9.0\Common7\IDE\</td>
					<td>
						Contains the directory of <c>DEVENV.EXE</c> (including the trailing backslash).
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>$(SolutionPath)</td>
					<td>D:\MySolution\Solution1.sln</td>
					<td>
						Contains the fully qualified path of the Visual Studio solution.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>$(SolutionDir)</td>
					<td>D:\MySolution\</td>
					<td>
						Contains the directory of the Visual Studio solution (including the trailing backslash).
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>$(SolutionFileName)</td>
					<td>Solution1.sln</td>
					<td>
						Contains the file name of the Visual Studio solution (excluding the directory path and including
						the file extension).
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>$(SolutionName)</td>
					<td>Solution1</td>
					<td>
						Contains the file name of the Visual Studio solution (excluding both the directory path and
						file extension).
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>$(SolutionExt)</td>
					<td>.sln</td>
					<td>
						Contains only the extension of the Visual Studio solution (including the period).
					</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
			<p>
				To use a macro just include it in any of the settings mentioned above. For example, assuming
				Clone Detective has been installed to <c>C:\Program Files (x86)\Clone Detective\</c> a value for
				<b>Analysis file</b> of <c>$(InstallDir)DefaultCloneDetection.cqa</c> will be extended to
				<c>C:\Program Files (x86)\Clone Detective\DefaultCloneDetection.cqa</c>.
			</p>
		</section>
	</body>
</topic>
